好了 别动 宝贝
Okay, hold still, honey.
我怕你又打到我身上
I'm afraid you're going to hit me again.
别担心 我这次只练推杆
Don't worry. I'm just putting this time.
我不是最厉害的高尔夫球手
I'm not the strongest golfer,
我觉得那拖累了我的生意
and I think it's holding me back in business.
真遗憾卖房合同不是在蹦床公园谈成的
Too bad deals aren't closed in a trampoline park.
我可以先屈体做一个鲁道尔夫
I'd just lazy-back into a Rudolph
然后做个哥特夫斯 在公司一步高升
into a quadriffus right up the corporate ladder.
老爸 你今晚要来看我的歌剧吗
Hey, dad, you coming to my play tonight?
你的歌剧 你不过是个画布景的
"Your" Play? You only painted the sets.
是啊 米开朗奇罗也不过画了西斯廷教堂
Yeah, and Michelangelo "Only" painted the Sixteenth Chapel.
或许你不该把脸凑得离油漆罐太近[毒晕]
Maybe don't keep your face so close to the paint cans.
抱歉 伙计 我要上高尔夫课
Sorry, buddy, I'm getting a golf lesson
然后得和一位客户打球
and then I'm playing with a client,
但你下次表演我会尽力去看的
But I'll try to make your next performance.
-菲尔 -小忙哦
-Phil! - Little busy.
你总是这样
Oh, you always do this.
完全不动脑子就把东西塞进冰箱里
You cram stuff in the freezer without thinking about it.
我一打开门 冰冻的火鸡差点砸我脚上
I opened the door, and a frozen turkey almost fell on my foot.
我老是打得偏左
I keep pulling it to the left.
你确定这房子是水平的吗
Are we sure the house is level?
你一点都不感到抱歉吗
Are you not the least bit sorry?
我的脚趾头差点断了
I could have broken a toe.
亲爱的 我每天都要为一堆
Honey, I'm sorry for dozens of things
实际发生的事情道歉
every day that actually happen.
如果我连没发生的事情都要道歉
If I start apologizing for things that don't happen,
我还能干成什么事儿啊
how productive of a person would I be?
你的高尔夫教授来了
Hey, your golf pro's here!
-大家好啊 -大家好啊
- Hola, hola. - Hello, everybody!
非常感谢你来给我上速成课 杰
Thanks so much for the quick lesson, Jay.
把我当作一块粘土
Just think of me as a blob of clay,
静候你那经验丰富的双手
waiting for your experienced hands
来爱抚 雕琢
to caress and coax me--
高尔夫第一法则 别废话
First rule of golf-- shh.
-好吧 -很好
- Okay. - Good.
如果你打算这么臭脾气一整天
If you're going to be a grump all day,
当初为什么要答应来教他
why did you even say that you were going to teach him?
因为我那些外孙就靠他吃饭了
Because he's how my grandkids get food.
他在这啊
There he is.
太感谢你答应照顾宝宝了
Ay, thank you so much for taking care of the baby.
小卡让我帮他的歌剧打杂
Cam has me running all kinds of errands for the play.
是吗 那你得时刻注意来电显示了
Yeah, well, you gotta keep your eye on the caller I.D.
我得去干洗店拿戏服
I have to go to the dry cleaners to pick up the costumes...
然后去拿干冰用来造雾
Then I have to go get the dry ice for the fog machine.
可能还得给小卡买些花
And maybe I'll go get Cam some flowers.
艾丽克斯可以帮你
Oh, Alex can help you with all that.
太棒了 好了 走吧
Oh, perfect. Okay, let's go.
我们不能迟到
We can't be late,
不然可就没有干冰 只能泪流满面了
or there won't be any dry ice in the house.
-说得不错 -什么
- Good one. - What?
你们都去好好玩吧 去吧 别担心
You guys have fun. Go on. Nothing to worry about.
我这里没问题
I got it handled here.
小心点
Be careful.
别担心 嘴巴张着就行
Don't worry, just keep your mouth open.
没事 真的没事
We're fine. It's fine.
好了 大家能静一静听我说吗
Okay, can I have everyone's attention, please?
罗本 我这里打个灯光
Reuben? Hit me with a spot.
太刺眼了 放个粉色滤光板上去
That's a little harsh. Throw a pink gel on that.
太棒了 很好
That's great. Perfect.
好了 我会录下今天的排练
All right, I will be recording today's rehearsal,
但你们别在镜头前感觉不自在
but don't let that make you self-conscious.
我只会用这个来指出你们的错误
I'm only using it to pinpoint your mistakes.
第二 我让全体剧组成员
Secondly, I have granted full set access
都能见到莫琳·希克
to Maureen Schick,
她今晚将来看你们的表演
who will be reviewing your show tonight.
完了 她很恶毒的
Uh-oh, she's vicious.
我们的前任音乐老师纳玛奇先生
Our last music teacher, Mr. Namagachi,
读了她的文章《烂得一团糟》 心碎难平
never recovered from her article, "Anything blows."
但公平地说 我看过那场表演
But in fairness, I saw that production,
女高音主角绝对是灾难
and the lead soprano was an absolute disaster.
无意冒犯 苏菲
No offense, Sophie.
你从那以后就全面绽放了 亲爱的
You've blossomed since then, sweetie, okay?
不要给她的麦克风装电池 好吗 很好
No batteries in her mic, okay? Great.
最后 马库斯·塔伯特
And lastly, Marcus Talbot.
伙计们 他感觉不太舒服
Guys, he's feeling a little under the weather.
不要怕 他在家养精蓄"嗓"呢
Fear not. He's home resting his instrument,
他今晚还是能登台表演
and he will be ready for the show tonight.
但现在需要一个替身来排练
But I will need a phantom for this rehearsal.
所以 谁上
So, anyone...
我想我能试试
I guess I could help.
我不知道马库斯是怎么当上主角的
I don't know how Marcus ever got the lead.
但我知道他是怎么生病的
But I know how he got sick--
就因为他那矫揉造作的恶心表演
from chewing all that scenery.
现在是我从那个虚伪的冒牌货手中
This was my chance to earn it back
夺回主角的机会
from that insincere phony.
但首先 先为可怜的马库斯做个默祷吧
But first, a silent prayer for our fallen captain marcus.
祝好运 老朋友
Godspeed, old friend.
好无聊啊 他死了吗
This is boring. Is he dead?
没有 他没死 他在睡觉呢
No, he's not dead. He's just sleeping.
婴儿需要很多睡眠
Babies need to sleep a lot
才能长得更大 更强壮 更聪明
so they grow bigger and stronger and smarter.
邓太太好 露西你好啊
Hey, Mrs. D. Hey, Lucy.
每次都叫错
Every time.
T恤不错嘛
Well, that's a nice shirt.
谢谢 我自己设计的
Thanks. I designed it myself.
是最畅销的一款
It's my best seller.
我真嫉妒你的生活如此有目标
I'm so jealous you know what you want to do with your life.
我要是想你一样志向远大就好了
I wish I was inspired like you.
或者 目标更高远一些
Or, you know, aim higher.
你得去体验些新鲜事物
Open yourself up to some new experiences
然后发现什么
and find out what--
-我的天 -你还好吗
- Oh, my g-- - are you okay?
没事 只是
Fine. Just...
又踩到你爸该死的高尔夫球了
slipped on one of your father's stupid golf balls.
很好 你吵醒他了
Good, you woke him up.
他可能是饿了 我刚刚喂了他
Maybe he's hungry. I just fed him,
但我觉得奶粉总是比不上母乳
but I don't think bottles can live up to the real thing.
也许我能让他安静下来
Maybe I can calm him down.
你真贴心 但他今天超级烦躁
Oh, that's very sweet of you, but he's super fussy today.
宝宝一旦烦躁 他们 他们
And when babies are fussy, they--they...
对啊 我超擅长哄宝宝的
Yeah, I'm good with babies.
你应该看他玩躲猫猫 他超级厉害
You should see him play peek-a-boo. He's amazing.
没有啦 只是不错而已
No. I'm good.
我认识一个芝加哥的家伙 他才厉害
I know a guy in Chicago-- he's amazing.
该死
Dang it!
开什么玩笑 草皮像火箭一样飞出去了
Are you kiddin' me? That divot flew out of there like a rocket.
我决定对菲尔友好些
I decided to go gentle with Phil,
那对我来说不容易
which didn't come easy to me,
因为一旦涉及运动
because I've always been a bit of a drill sergeant
我就变得像操练军士一样严格
when it comes to sports.
但对于新宝宝
And with the new baby,
歌洛莉亚总是埋怨我不够耐心
Gloria's been buggin' me to have more patience.
拜托 他都好好存活一个月了
But come on. He's been alive a month.
支撑着小脑袋不掉能有多难
How hard is it to support your own head?
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
好啊 小伙子们
Hello, boys.
车不错啊 胡娇
What a sweet ride, Pepper.
你们在这里干嘛
What are you guys doing here?
我已经练习高尔夫几周的时间了
I've been golfing for a few weeks.
胡娇一直在教我
Pepper's been teaching me.
我从小就和我父亲一起打高尔夫
I grew up golfing with my father,
伟大的海亚姆·萨尔茨曼
the great Chaim Saltzman.
他在俱乐部广为人知的名字就是
Or as he was known around the clubhouse,
查德·特德维尔
Chad Treadwell.
我们该来一个"四人行"
Well, we should play together as a foursome.
我第一次被这词吓着了 不过好吧
First time that word's creeped me out, but okay.
你介意我增加点趣味吗
Care to make it interesting?
我觉得你的裤子已经很够"趣味"了
I think your pants have already done that.
赌100美元怎么样
How 'bout a hundred bucks?
我和菲尔对阵[玩弄]你和米奇
Me and Phil will play you and Mitch.
行啊 米奇尔 你先上好吗
Fun. Mitchell, care to go first?
我...
Oh, I...
好的 我 我挥一个试试
Okay. Yeah. I'll-- I'll give it a whirl.
碰上我爸绝非偶然
Running into my dad was no accident.
我天生就不擅长体育运动
I wasn't the best athlete growing up,
而我爸绝不会错过任何一次
and my dad never missed an opportunity
指出这一点的机会
to point that out.
"扔的不错 南茜"
"Nice throw, Nancy!"
南茜是我们的邻居
Nancy was our neighbor.
我扔球永远不如她
I could never throw as well as she could.
我几乎放弃了在任何事上打败我爸的想法
I'd pretty much given up on beating my dad at anything
直到某天 胡娇把我拉到高尔夫球场
until Pepper dragged me to a golf course one day.
事实表明 我打得很好
Turns out I wasn't half bad.
经过六个月的练习
Six months' practice later,
我已经准备好打败我爸
I was ready to kick my dad's ass.
我都想好了打败他的过程
I knew just how I was gonna do it, too.
我会很紧张地走到球座旁
I'd walk up to the tee all nervous,
笨拙地练习几下挥杆
do a few clumsy practice swings,
然后直击球的中部
and then I'd hit that ball dead center,
目送它划过天际 直落在草坪之上
watch it arc through the sky, land on the green,
让我爸赞叹地喊出"哇"
and totally wow my dad.
噢不
Oh, no.
哇
Wow.
*夜的乐章 已经结束*
*It's over now, the music of the night*
好的 做得好 所有人
Okay. Great job, everyone.
谢谢你 但真是靠所有人的共同努力
Thank you. But it was really everyone.
为自己喝彩吧
Give yourself a round.
马库斯的母亲 嘘
Oh, Marcus's mom. Shh.
祈求好运吧
Fingers crossed.
你怎么还没干完
Why is it taking you so long?
漆个墙面能有多难
How hard is it to paint a wall?
可比你们所谓的演唱难多了
A lot harder than your so-called singing.
至少墙漆出来就该是平的[音不准]
At least this is supposed to be flat.
我以前看过猴子漆墙
I once saw a monkey paint a wall.
是吗 那你有没有说 "干得好 妈妈"
Yeah? Did you say, "Good job, mom"?
单核血球增多症 可他是我的主角
Mono? But he's my lead.
我的事业全靠这部剧了
My career depends upon this.
区政府差这么一点儿就要削减我的经费了
The district is this close to cutting my funding,
我的两根手指现在比划得很靠近
and my fingers are very close together right now.
-*夜晚* -让我和马库斯谈谈
- *Nighttime* - Just let me talk to Marcus.
-*加剧* -他绝不会背弃这些同伴的
- *Sharpens* -he would never turn his back on this company.
我们就像一家人一样
We are like family here.
*让人浮想联翩*
*Stirs imagination*
不好意思 我们另想办法
I'm sorry. We're going another way.
*感官悄无声息*
*Silently the senses*
*放下它的防备*
*Abandon their defenses*
马库斯有什么消息吗
Any news about Marcus?
-你为什么小声说话 -保护嗓子以防万一
- Why are you whispering? - Saving my voice, just in case.
马库斯已经出局了
Oh. Well, marcus is out.
幸运的是我在这里找到了一位更出色的魅影
But luckily, I found an even better phantom right here.
我不会说自己更好 不过既然你说了...
I wouldn't say better, but since you did...
卢克 我正要去问他
Luke. I was just about to ask him.
-卢克 -他了解剧情
- Luke? - He knows the show,
他唱得如夜莺般动人
he sings like a nightingale,
而且他眼中有一种对戏剧的疯狂
and he has a certain theatrical madness in his eyes
那是教不来的
you cannot teach.
那是油漆造成的吧
That's just from all the paint.
卢克
Oh. Uh, Luke?
停下 你难道想吓到他吗
Stop it. Are you trying to spook him?
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
你批评完他画的布景 他就已经被你吓到了
He's already intimidated by you after you criticized his sets.
拜托 不会只有我一个人觉得
Oh, please. I could not be the only person
他画的独角兽会让人分神吧
that found his unicorns distracting.
让我先跟他说吧
Let me talk to him first.
要是我说服不了他 你再来
If I can't get the job done, then you step in...
现在的情况有点像替补演员
Kind of like the way an understudy
在主演出状况时候挺身而出什么的
would traditionally take over when the lead finds himself--
行了 去吧
Yeah. Just do it.
卢克 或者我应该叫你 魅影
Hey there, luke. Or should I say, phantom?
你有话直说好吗
You wanna get to the point?
因为我还有事要忙
'cause I'm kind of on a schedule,
而且那油漆味总让我闻着摔倒
and this paint keeps making me fall down.
马库斯出局了 小卡希望由你顶替他
Marcus is out, and Cam wants you to take over.
真的吗 所有的歌曲我还真都会
Really? Well, I do know all the songs.
不要试图让自己放弃 你一定要做
Stop trying to talk yourself out of it. You're doing it.
只不过两晚而已
It's only for two nights.
你又来了 只知道看消极因素
You're doing it again, looking at the negatives.
看好的方面 万一你没有搞砸
Look at the bright side. What if you don't screw up,
没有丢脸 或是被永远嘲笑
humiliate yourself, and get mocked forever?
-我会被人嘲笑吗 -只是被那些酷小孩而已
- I'd get mocked? - Only by the cool kids.
不过谁需要他们
But who needs them?
你现在已经属于我们的队伍了
You're one of us now.
歌剧奇客
The theater geeks.
*佛蒙特州雪满天*
*Vermont is snowy*
*拉斯维加斯太耀眼*
*Las vegas is showy*
*那就是我记得的大城市*
*And those are the capitals I remember*
如果这个放在楼梯最上一阶会怎样
what if this had been at the top of the stairs?
我一定会伤得很严重 对吧
I mean, I really could have gotten hurt, right?
对 莉莉 我给你做了午饭
Uh-huh. Lily, I made you lunch.
花生酱 我的最爱
Peanut butter. My favorite.
真难让人相信
It's just hard to believe
居然有人会对如此显眼的
that somebody could be so oblivious
安全隐患视而不见
to a situation that is clearly dangerous.
看看我们 我们就像一个小家庭
Look at us. We're like a little family.
我知道
I know.
-我们是一对家长 -我知道
- We're the parents. - I know!
我知道他的反应一定是
I know what his response would be--
"可你又没什么事 为什么要大发雷霆"
"But you're fine. Why you getting all bent out of shape?"
不过万一我出了什么事呢
But what if I wasn't fine?
万一他一进家门
What if he walked through the door,
就以为自己制造了一场可怕的事故呢
And he thought he had created a horrible accident?
这可太好玩了
Oh, this is so fun.
太好了 她走了
Good. She's gone.
拿你的相机来
Grab your camera.
我要再让他竖个小中指
I'm gonna make his little hand flip us off again.
不 不只我一个人
No, it's not just me.
三位妈妈一起办的这个派对
Three mothers are giving the party,
我们的名字都要在卡片上
and we need all our names in the card--
歌洛莉亚·普里契特 莎拉·莱纳德 迪·乔
Gloria Pritchett, Sara Leonard, Dee Cho...
什么叫没地方写了
What do you mean that there's no more room?
迪·乔必须写上去
Dee Cho must go on.
得了吧 那家伙显然是故意的
Okay, come on. That one had to be on purpose.
好吧 那我们等会到
Okay, we'll be there then.
他们还要一个小时才能做好
They won't be ready until one more hour.
要不要换你来拿干冰
You maybe wanna take a shift carrying this dry ice?
不要 我刚生完宝宝
No, I just had a baby.
我都看到你把曼尼扛上床了
I've watched you carry Manny to bed.
我知道我们要怎么打发时间了
I know what we can do to kill time.
我的灵媒就住拐角那里
My psychic is around the corner.
求你告诉我你刚说的是"密友"
Please tell me you just said "sidekick."
曾经我也以为我是无所不知的
I used to think that I knew everything, too.
我们去算个命吧
We're going for a reading.
我先通知她我们马上就到
I'll let her know that we're coming.
你逗我玩儿吧
You have got to be kidding me.
我是在想电话号码是多少
I'm trying to remember the telephone number.
我是怎么回事
What is happening to me?
好吧 我们输了3杆了吗
All right, what are we, 3 strokes down now?
我觉得某人需要听听"胡言娇语"
I think someone needs a Pepper talk.
那怎么算是"胡言娇语"
How is that a Pepper talk?
你得愤怒起来 野蛮一点
You need to get angry. Play aggressive.
那男人几乎扇了你一辈子的耳光
That man's been mitch-slapping you and your entire life.
我知道 但是 他现在对菲尔真好
I know, but... he's being so nice to Phil,
而菲尔可比我糟糕多了
and Phil is way worse than I ever was.
我不知道
I don't know.
也许他不是曾经那个没有同情心的混球了
Maybe he's not the unsympathetic jerk he used to be.
好吧 你刚刚开局不利
Okay, so you got off to a rough start.
简要地说
Let's simplify.
在这一球 我要你把注意力集中在
On this shot, I want you to just concentrate
弯曲膝盖上
on bending your knees.
-懂了吗 -弯曲膝盖
- You got it? - Bend my knees.
弯曲--
Bend my--
见鬼 伸直膝盖
Dang it! Straighten my knees.
妈的 你就是个扶不起的阿斗
Son of a bitch, you're a hopeless embarrassment.
你踢起来的沙子 比海龟下蛋踢得还多
You're kickin' up more sand than a sea turtle layin' eggs.
你看见了没
Did you see that?!
嗯 不算糟嘛
Yeah, that wasn't half bad.
嘿 抱歉刚才对你吼了
Hey, listen, I'm sorry I yelled.
不 不 不 我需要的就是这个
No, no, no. That's what I needed.
我大学时代的摔跤教练总是吼我
My old tumbling master in college used to yell at me all the time.
那会让我变得更强
It just made me better.
-真的吗 -真的
- Really? - Oh, yeah.
他强烈侮辱我的男子汉气概
He'd say terrible things about my manhood,
他还拿粉袋扔我
He'd throw the chalk bag at me,
他奚落了我一整个夏天 让我变猛
He'd call me and taunt me over the summer to keep me sharp.
所以放马过来吧 杰
So bring it, Jay!
你太逊了 菲尔
You stink, Phil.
你是高尔夫史上 自允许穿短裤以来
You're the worst thing to happen to golf
最糟糕的存在
since they let people wear shorts.
你刚刚让我--
You just told me to--
不 流泪也是其中一部分
No, that's part of it.
听到了没
Did you hear that?
并且他不只是在训菲尔
And he wasn't just talking to Phil.
他也是在训10岁的你
He was talking to 10-year-old you
12岁的你
and 12-year-old you and...
去你妈的 南茜
Suck it, Nancy!
我只不过想帮帮忙而已
I was just trying to help.
打开心扉好好听
Just listen with an open mind.
她不相信灵媒
She doesn't believe in psychics.
不只是灵媒
It's not just psychics.
所有无法量化的现象我都不信
It's all unquantifiable phenomena.
我还是给你省点时间吧
I'm going to save you some time.
她没有男朋友
She doesn't have a boyfriend.
可能现在没有 但很快就有了
Maybe not now, but soon.
看到没
You see?
-那说明 -嘘 继续
- That means-- - Shh. Go on.
你会遇见一个特别的人
You are going to meet someone special.
我看到一个英俊的男人 骑着马
I see a handsome man on a horse,
就像一位骑士
like a knight.
我这个周末要去参加文艺复兴集会
Well, I am going to a renaissance fair this weekend.
是啊 我知道
Yes, I know.
根本就没有什么文艺复兴集会
There's no renaissance fair.
就算有 我也不会去
Even if there was, I wouldn't go.
不然会成为小天文学家俱乐部的笑柄
I'd be the laughingstock of the young astronomer's club.
可我不能告诉歌洛莉亚她的预言家是骗子
But I couldn't tell Gloria her fortune-teller was a fake...
至少在我找到更多乐子之前
Not until I had a little more fun.
我看到你笑了 你很享受哦
I see that you're smiling. You're enjoying yourself.
我知道这听起来很疯癫
I know it sounds crazy,
你能告诉我 在我5岁那年
But could you please tell me what happened to
跑了的兔子"小纽扣" 它怎么了吗
myy bunny Buttons, who ran away when I was 5?
根本就没有什么兔子 我讨厌兔子
Never had a bunny. Hate bunnies.
我看到一个农场
I see a farm...
有个红色的谷仓
with a red barn.
我知道谁在谷仓里
I know who's in the barn!
那就像跟海莉玩拼字游戏
It's like scrabble with Haley.
玩了一会 你就是在和自己玩了
After a while, you're just playing against yourself.
好了大家 都打起精神
Okay, everyone, look sharp, please!
媒体过来了
The press is here!
如我所说 莫琳 我真的很沾光
As I was saying, Maureen, I was really at an advantage
我看过百老汇版本
having seen the broadway production.
我能从他们的错误里吸取教训
I was able to learn from their mistakes.
比如 在我的作品中
For example, in my production,
魅影在第一幕中出场
The phantom appears in the first scene,
因为它毕竟不是叫做
because after all, it's not called
"歌剧克里斯蒂和拉乌尔"
"Christine and Raoul of the opera."
我有两个线人报告说
I have two sources telling me
你的主角得了水痘在家休息
your lead is home with chicken pox.
-是单核血球增多症 -那你就是第三个线人了
- Uh, mono. - Make that three sources.
可恶 你真行啊
Oh, damn, you're good.
我可以 私底下透露个消息吗
Um, permission to speak... off the record?
不可以
Denied.
好吧 那么
Okay, fine. Well, then...
你自己等着看吧
See for yourself in just a moment.
今晚将有巨星横空出世
Tonight a star will be born.
-小卡 -等等 曼尼 我在造星呢
- Cam? - Not now, Manny. I'm birthing something.
有时候在剧场里
Sometimes in the theater,
真正的戏剧在帷幕升起之前就上演了
the real drama happens before the curtain rises.
看好了
Observe.
卢克·邓菲
Luke Dunphy,
你要不要演卡梅隆·塔克拍的
How would you like to play the starring role
安德鲁·劳埃德·韦伯的
in Cameron Tucker's Andrew Lloyd Webber's
《歌剧魅影》的主角
"Phantom of the Opera"?
不想
Nope.
卢克·邓菲 你拒绝的原因
Luke Dunphy, is it true you passed
是你和蛮横的导演之间存在创意分歧吗
because of creative differences with an overbearing director?
别理那个挑事的记者
Say nothing to that jackal!
曼尼 怎么回事
Manny, what happened?
我尽力了
I tried my best.
但他光是想想就已经喘不过气来了
He started hyperventilating just thinking about it.
我想有些人就是承受不了成为焦点的压力
I guess some people just aren't comfortable taking center stage.
好吧 也许我们可以给马库斯打一针
Okay. Well, maybe we can pump Marcus
那种给自行车手们打的东西
full of whatever they gave those bike riders.
他病得太重了
He's too sick.
但别担心 小卡 你会想到办法的
But don't worry, Cam, you'll think of something.
黎明前总是最黑暗的
It's always darkest right before the...
罗本 你能把聚光灯拿稳了吗
Reuben, could you keep that thing still?!
好吧 看来我们只有一个办法了
Okay, well, I guess we only have one option.
-我愿意 -什么
- I'll do it. - Hmm?
我本来是想说自己来演的
I was gonna say play the role myself,
但我想还是该给孩子们一个机会
but, you know, I guess it really should be about the kids.
现在假设我被你爸的高尔夫球绊倒
Now if I had tripped on your father's golf ball,
比如...从楼梯上摔了下去
say... top of the stairs,
也许会...噢不
probably would have--oh, no!
碰掉几幅相框
Taken out some pictures.
瞧你干的好事 菲尔
Look what you've done, Phil!
妈
Mom!
没事 他总算睡着了
It's okay. It's finally sleeping.
我们来拍张合照吧
Hey, we should take a picture of all of us.
一旦你摔下来 就控制不了自己了
Then once you get going, you know, you just can't stop.
看见什么抓什么
You're taking everything down with you.
然后 为了让你爸清楚地知道
And then, to make it perfectly clear
到底是怎么回事
to your father what happened,
我要把高尔夫球放在这里
I'll put the golf ball right here,
因为有些人就是
because some people can't see the danger
不亲眼看见就意识不到危险的存在
unless it's right under their nose.
养孩子真好玩
Having kids is fun.
也很容易
And easy.
也许我的人生目标就是相夫教子
Maybe this is what I should do with my life.
他真是个小天使 我也想生一个
Oh, he's such a little angel. I want one.
小点声 海莉 小家伙需要睡眠
Haley, little dude needs his sleep.
我本想告诉海莉
I wanted to tell Haley
太早结婚生子的危害有多大
about the dangers of starting a family too early,
但我说什么
but what could I say
能比婴儿的哭闹声更奏效呢
that couldn't be said better by a screaming baby?
妈
Mom!
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
我也不知道我今天是怎么了
I don't know what's wrong with me today.
-妈 -照睡不误
- Mom! - Still good.
-抱歉 -你能离开这间屋子吗
- Sorry. - Would you just get out of here?
可以 可以 真抱歉
Yeah. Yeah. Totally sorry.
我...
It's my--
抱歉
Sorry.
等他醒了 我们一起出去买冰激凌吃吧
When he wakes up, we should all go out for ice cream.
我也是这么想的
I was thinking the same thing.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
不关你的事
Minding my own business.
等等 莉莉吃了冰激凌就吃不下晚饭了
Wait. Ice cream might ruin Lily's dinner.
所以呢
So?
我花了整个下午的时间做晚饭
So I spent all afternoon cooking.
我觉得去吃冰激凌比较欢乐
I thought ice cream would be fun.
你一整天都在找乐子
All you've done today is have fun
脏活累活都是我干的
while I did all the work.
我只是想尽量享受和孩子们在一起的时间
I'm just trying to make the most of it with these kids.
我不像你总能和他们在一起
I don't have as much time with them as you do.
所以你就溺爱他们是吗
What, by spoiling them?
是谁 谁给你发的短信
Who's that? Who's texting you?
只是工作上的事
It's just about work.
你总是这样 就算在家里也心不在焉的
Typical. Even when you're here, you're not here.
吃个冰激凌你干嘛生这么大气
Why are you this upset about ice cream?
你要是觉得我是因为冰激凌而生气
If that's what you think this is about,
说明你根本没有听我说话
then you haven't heard a word I've said!
我被你绕晕了 我们为什么要管这些孩子
I-I'm confused. Why do we even have these kids?
我不知道
I don't know!
我回家了
I'm going home!
太好了
Good!
真"好"
Oh, fantastic.
离球洞还有最后一击
One stroke down on the final hole.
真是个大推杆 真是个大大的推杆
It's such a big putt. Such a big, big putt.
我喜欢"大屁屁" 我无法否认
I like big putts, and I cannot lie.
说得好
Money.
你知道什么很可悲吗 你努力地练习
You know what'll be sad? You doing all that practicing
就为了能击败你老爸
to finally be able to beat your old man,
结果还是没成功
And coming up just short.
我真是
I almost...
不忍心看了
can't watch.
你该上了 高手
You're up, ace.
我和我爸也像他们这样
I was the same way with my father.
我们的关系总是很复杂
It's always complicated.
我和我爸没有 他什么事都支持我
Not for mine. My dad was just supportive.
从没错过一场我的摔跤表演
Never missed a tumbling meet
或是霹雳舞比赛
or a break-dance brawl.
我如果为我们的学校集会设置音响系统
Heck, I'd set up the sound system for our school assembly,
他一定是人群中声音最大的
he'd be the loudest voice in the crowd.
"各位 来瞧瞧我儿子的设备"
"Hey, everybody! Check out my son's equipment!"
-哇 -是啊
- Aw. - Yeah.
说真的 祝你好运
Hey, seriously, good luck.
你打得不错 我为你骄傲
You played good. I'm proud of you.
-真的吗 -我们应该多出来一起打球
- Really? - We should do this again sometime.
别听他的
Don't listen to him.
他在对你施展"摇篮里的猫"战术
He's "Cat's in the Cradling" you.
-什么 -他在影响你的情绪
- What? - He's playing on your emotions
好让你失去斗志
so you lose your edge.
我也总那样对我儿子
I do it to my son all the time.
他刚刚是说他有儿子吗
Did he say "Son"?
是的 他是海豹突击队的
Yes. He's a Navy Seal.
我透露得太多了
Oh, I've said too much.
"摇篮里的猫"是什么意思
What's "Cats in the Cradle"?
就是那首关于一个父亲的歌
You know, that song about the dad who misses
他错过了儿子人生中每个重要时刻
all the important moments in his kid's life?
你要坚强不屈
Stay strong,
就像我家凯尔在也门时那样
just like Kyle did in Yemen.
天呐 我真是个大嘴巴
Oh, my god, I'm a sieve.
好了 米奇 上吧
All right, Mitch. Showtime.
五 六
Five. Six.
五 六 七 八
A-five, six, seven, eight.
好耶
Yes!
一百块到手
A hundred bucks!
我们成功了
Oh, we did it!
我总算能买得起配这条裤子的上衣了
Now I can afford the shirt that matches these pants.
要去会所喝两杯吗
So... drinks in the clubhouse?
不行 我儿子在演出呢
Can't. My kid's in a play.
我约了个客户来再打一轮高尔夫
Yeah, I'm meeting a client for another round of golf.
你如果看到卢克 替我给他个拥抱好吗
Hey, if you see Luke, will you give him a hug for me?
当然 我说真的
Will do. Hey, I was serious
我们改天一起打球
about we should play again sometime.
想来挺傻的
It's a crazy thing
如果你小时候我对你没那么严厉
that if I'd been less of a hard head when you were a kid,
这20年来 我们本可以父子齐上阵的
we could have had 20 years in this dumb game.
不 我也有一半责任
No, it was half my fault.
我以前内心太脆弱了
I mean, I-I used to be pretty sensitive.
你真的没有对我施展
So y-you really weren't
《摇篮里的猫咪》战术吗
"Cat's in the cradling" me back there?
当然没有
Of course not.
你们说的这首歌 我怎么从来没听过
How have I not heard of this song you keep talking about?
-不听也罢 太难听了 -太伤感了
- You have. It's the worst. - It's the schmaltziest.
难以忍受
Unbearable.
我回去的路上放给你听 我的iPod上有
I'll play it on the way back. I have it on my iPod phone.
*摇篮里的猫咪*
*And the cat's in the cradle*
*含着金匙出生*
*And the silver spoon*
*小男孩很伤感 爸爸要出远门*
*Little boy blue and the man on the moon*
*你什么时候回家 爸爸*
*When you coming home, dad?*
*我不知道什么时候*
*I don't know when,*
*但回来时父子便能相聚*
*But we'll get together then.*
*回来时我们便能共度好时光*
*You know we'll have a good time then*
我应该早点和你一起打高尔夫的 爸
I should have golfed with you sooner, dad.
我总是没空
I never made the time.
卢克
Luke!
我要打电话给我儿子
I need to call my son.
现在大马士革是几点
What time is it in Damascus?
我还是画张地图算了
Why don't I just draw them a map?
准备好了吗 菲尔
Ready to play, Phil?
我没空 卡尔 我儿子画布景的歌剧要开演了
I can't, Carl! My boy's sets are in a play!
我感觉到你认识的人
I get the feeling that something wonderful
最近碰到了好事
has happened to someone you know.
对 是曼尼
Yes, it's Manny.
他在学校歌剧中做主角
He got the lead role in the school play.
对 就是这个
Yes, that's it.
好吧 我觉得你已经取悦她一半了
Okay, I think you might have met her halfway on that one.
你们感觉到了吗
Do you feel that?
一个鬼魂刚刚进入了房间
A presence has just entered the room.
可能是空调的凉风吹过
Or the A.C. kicked in.
歌洛莉亚 我有话要说
Gloria, I have to say something.
是你的祖母
It's your abuela.
哪一位
Which one?
她抽的是烟斗还是雪茄
Is she smoking a pipe, or is she smoking a cigar?
雪茄
A cigar.
是我的外祖母
My mother's mother.
我好想她
I miss her so much.
她说她也想你
She says she misses you, too.
我真希望她能见见我那刚出生的小儿子
I wish that she was here now to see Fulgencio Joe.
她见到了
She has seen him,
而且她说孩子好漂亮
and she says he is beautiful.
他的确漂亮吧
He is, isn't he?
告诉她我爱她
Tell her that I love her.
她知道
She knows.
非常感谢
Thank you so much for that.
瞧见了吗
You see now?
我想我都瞧见了
I think I do.
*夜之乐章*
*The music of the night*
曼尼 我问个问题
Okay, Manny, quick question.
你是忘了我说的要点
Did you forget the notes I gave you
还是选择无视它们
or just choose to ignore them?
你这是做什么
Where are you going with that?
前排要加个座位
We need an extra one up front.
纳玛奇老师决定来看演出
Mr. Namagachi decided to come.
你是说我顶替的那位不为人师表的老师
Oh, you mean the disgraced teacher I replaced
突然对这出歌剧有兴趣吗
suddenly has an interest in this production?
他正在停车
He's parking his peugeot right now.
哇 等着看我出丑的秃鹰正式杀到了
Wow, the vultures are officially circling.
曼尼 我就不隐瞒了
Okay, Manny, it's no secret
你并不是我的第一人选
that you were not my first choice for this,
也不是第二
or my second.
但现在对你来说还不算迟
But it's not too late for you
你还有机会唱出属于自己的魅影
to make this your very own phantom.
所以我要你看卢克的演唱
So I want you to watch what Luke did,
模仿就行
and copy that.
*感官悄无声息*
*Silently the senses*
-*放下它的防备* -他太出色了
- *Abandon their...* - He was glorious.
每一个音符 每一处神韵 我如入天堂
Every note, every nuance... I was transported,
我也无比生气
and I was furious.
但我不是生卢克的气
But my quarrel wasn't with Luke.
而是上帝
It was with god.
帮你姐占个座位
Save a seat for your sister.
抱歉 我想那是我的座位
Excuse me. I think that's my seat.
爸 你怎么来了
Dad! What are you doing here?
开什么玩笑
Are you kiddin' me?
这出歌剧里的布景是我孙子画的
My grandson paints the sets for a play,
我岂有不从弗州开车来的道理
and I'm not gonna drive in from Florida, hmm?
这个座位有人吗
Is this one taken?
请坐
All yours.
这件运动衫
That sweatshirt...
我是网球队的
I'm on the tennis team.
我们是山谷科学骑士队
We're the valley science knights.
骑士
The knights?
*夜已深*
*Nighttime sharpens*
*感情升温*
*Heightens each sensation*
-什么 -*黑暗让...*
- What? - *Darkness stirs*
-那是卢克 -不会吧
- That's Luke. - No.
*心灵放飞*
*And wakes imagination*
*感官悄无声息*
*Silently the senses*
-*放弃防备之心* -台上的本应是你
- *Abandon their defenses* - That could have been you out there.
算了 那样不对
No, it wouldn't have been right.
我肯定你还是可以唱对几个音的
I'm sure you would've gotten some of it right.
我不是这个意思
Not what I meant.
多谢你愿意在这里见我
Hey, thanks for meeting me here.
把生意与娱乐合二为一
No reason we can't mix business
并没有什么不好啊
with a little pleasure. Am I right?
我只是很高兴能碰到一个人和我一样
I'm just excited to find someone who enjoys this sport
喜欢这项运动
as much as I do.
我就开门见山吧 卡尔
I'm gonna be straight with you, Carl.
你有不少资产要出售
You got a ton of inventory to move,
你需要一个能干的地产经纪
and you're in need of a serious realtor.
上去
Hup hup!
在佣金方面 你有多坚持[稳定]
So how firm are you on your commission?
我想你可以看出来 我相当有"弹性"
As I think you can see, I'm quite flexible.
说实话 菲尔 我喜欢你
I'll be honest, Phil, I like you.
我想我愿意与你合作
I think I'm ready to move forward with this.
真的吗 我太高兴了
Really? Well, I'm thrilled.
知道吗 我们这就定下来吧
Hey, you know, we could make this official.
表现得真好 儿子
Nice form, son!
别误会 我是指那份合同
I'm talking about that contract, of course.
你还是这么风趣 爸
You still got it, dad.
那是我爸
That's my dad.
你好
Hi.